# **Gareth Patterson**

Charlotte, NC | patteg7@gmail.com | 973 908-9082 | LinkedIn | GitHub

### **SUMMARY**

Being fully self-taught, I have organically cultivated a deep interest in the software space. Coming from a people-oriented background, I find strength in my communication skills. Having served in client facing roles, I am strong in translating business needs into technology deliverables. Likewise, I breakdown complex topics into digestible pieces for stakeholders across all business functions. A track record of exceeding growth expectations in terms of technology and communication.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python

• MongoDB/NoSQL

• React.js

JavaScript/Node.js

• SQL/SQLite

• Cloud Computing

Linux/Bash

Django/Flask

Networking

Certifications: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900, AWS Certified Developer: Associate Expected August 2023

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Endava – IT Service and Consulting**

Capital Market BDR & Back-end Python Developer

Charlotte, NC Jan 2023 – Current

• POS for logistics projected, implementing my own algorithms optimizing efficiency.

• Communicate with clients on database capabilities, NoSQL, MySQL

• Software and Business value of Data Management, Trading Platforms build-out, Cloud Migration, AI

Conducted requirement gathering, Sales, Delivery, Legal, and Development teams.

# Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity

Growth Consultant

Charlotte, NC

Jun 2022-Dec 2022

• Calendar and SharePoint Organization for various projects

• Built Excel Budget to track \$400,000 per year using functions and Power Queries

## **Oxford Networking Systems**

IT Analyst

Raritan Center, NJ

Sep 2019–Jun 2022

- Supported internal data Networks while improving reliability
- Usage of Linux/MS to remotely access machines & troubleshooting network performance issues
- Manually fixed various pieces of hardware and maximized network efficiency

### **PROJECTS**

# Demeter with Endava | GitHub

Jul 2023-Current

Technologies: Postgres, Python, Django, React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Azure OpenAI

- Lead Developer on a POC to map a 3-dimension space and optimize storage.
- Utilized Django to create a REST API connected to a React.JS Frontend
- Created a chatbot that allowed users to easily track and move items throughout facility.
- Architected the connection of 10+ models and engineered their interactions

### Coffee & Bean | GitHub

Aug 2023—Current

Technologies: Python, Django, React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Docker

- Retail site with shopping cart storage system to track items and users.
- Utilized a NoSQL server backend that fully integrated with a REST API to React.JS
- Integrated products hosted on other websites to create a focal marketplace.

#### **Dynamic Automatic Stock Execution System | GitHub**

Aug 2023—Current

Technologies: Python, Flask, MongoDB, Yahoo Finance API, React.js, HTML, CSS

- Monitors the most traded stocks and executes basic trades based on statistical analysis.
- Dynamic Frontend that allows immersive changes to models and forecasts

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

Software Engineering

New York, NY

Expected Nov 2023

**Rutgers University** 

B.A. in History and Political Science

New Brunswick, NJ Graduated May 2022